Guide to the Victor F. Germack and Lori Shepard Germack Collection of Photographs of Indians of North America
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Printed Material and Press Kit, 1899-1975; Series VIII; 0.81; (4 boxes)
  - Prints
    - Offset Lithographs
      - Heyn, Herman
        Published by the Pittsburg Plate Glass Co.
        - Black Bird, American Indian Man (No. 140), 1899 (Box 18, Folder 1374)
        - Two Elk (Ogala Nopa), Dakota Indian Man (No. 1060), 1900 (Box 18, Folder 1375)
        - Poor Bull (Tatanka Tamaheca), Dakota Indian Man (No. 1063), 1900 (Box 18, Folder 1376)
      - Rinehart, Frank A.
        - Red Cloud or Scarlet Cloud (Makhpiya-luta, Mahpina Luta), Oglala Indian Man, 1900 (Box 18, Folder 1377)
        - Sitting Bull (Thatháŋka Íyotake), a Hunkpapa Indian Man, 1900 (Box 18, Folder 1378)
          The lithograph is affixed to board that advertises "Indian Portraits in Colors from the Perry Pictures Company."
      - Wm. Wrigley Jr. Company
        - Sitting Bull (Thatháŋka Íyotake), Lakota Indian Man, circa 1932 (Box 18, Folder 1379)
          Original photograph by William Notman.
          Promotional premium related to the Chief Wolf Paw and Lone Wolf Tribe Radio Program
    - Chromolithograph by the Detroit Photographic Co.
      - Studio Portrait of Chief Severo (Aaron Bear) and Ute Indian Men, Women and Children of his Family (No. 50324), 1900 (Box 24, Folder 1380)
        Original photograph by Charles A. Nast, circa 1885.
    - Photogravures by Edward Sheriff Curtis
      Photogravures from The North American Indian (1907-1930), by Edward S. Curtis, which depict representations of traditional American Indian culture.
      - The Oath - Apsaroke, 1908 (Box 24, Folder 1381)
        Photogravure print autographed by Curtis in 1911 and affixed to a sheet from a scrapbook probably compiled by Jean Simpson, 1911-1919.
      - Basket Maker (Plate 310), 1912 (Box 24, Folder 1382)
        Trimmed print.
      - Quamichan Lake (Plate 328), 1912 (Box 24, Folder 1383)
      - Painting a Hat - Nakoaktok (Plate 329), 1914 (Box 24, Folder 1384)
      - Siwit - Awaitlala (Plate 335), 1914 (Box 24, Folder 1385)
      - Kotsuis and Hohhug - Nakoaktok (Plate 336), 1914 (Box 24, Folder 1386)
      - Kwakiutl House-Frame (Plate 343), 1914 (Box 24, Folder 1387)
      - The Fisherman - Southern Miwok (Plate 496), 1924 (Box 24, Folder 1388)
  - Cigarette Cards
    Cigarette cards depicted pictures of animals, persons, or other popular culture subjects. They were packaged by manufacturers of cigarettes with their product during the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries.
    Associated Materials: Cigarette cards with mounted photographic prints can also be found in Series II. Card Photographs.
    - Celebrated American Indian Chiefs
      Issued by Allen & Ginter in 1888, the Celebrated American Indian Chiefs set depicts fifty different American Indian men in a complete set, not including cards with caption errors. The source images for the chromolithographic representations of American Indian men on many of the cards derive from photographs created during visits by American Indian delegations to Washington, D.C.
      Allen & Ginter was a tobacco manufacturing firm formed in Richmond, Virginia, by John Allen and Lewis Ginter in 1875. The firm created and marketed the first cigarette cards for collecting and trading.
      The entries for cards in this collection include parenthetical references for the correct tribal affiliation of the depicted individual when appropriate.
      - Cards from the Celebrated American Indian Chiefs Set, 1888; Housed in a wooden frame (Box 28)
        Wooden frame with an American Indian motif that holds 29 cards from the Celebrated American Indian Chiefs Set.
        Cards include: Agate Arrow Point, a Warm Springs Indian (Salish Indian); Always Riding, a Yampah Ute Indian; Big Bear, a Missouria Indian (Missouri Indian); Big Elk, a Ponca Indian; Big Razor, a Blackfeet Sioux Indian (Yanktonai Indian); Cayatanita, a Navajo Indian; Chief Joseph, a Nez Perce Indian; Clam Fish, a Warm Springs Indian (Warm Spring Apache Indian); Deer Ham, an Ioway Indian (Iowa Indian); Geronimo, an Apache Indian (Chiricahua Apache); Great Bear, a Delaware Indian (Delaware Indian); Grey Eagle, an Apache Indian; John Grass, a Blackfeet Sioux Indian (Sihasapa Indian); John Yellow Flower, a Ute Indian; Keokuk's Son, a Sac & Fox Indian; King of the Crows, a Crow Indian; Lean Wolf, a Gros Ventres Indian (Hidatsa Indian); Man and Chief, a Pawnee Indian; Many Horns, a Blackfeet Sioux Indian (Dakota Indian); Noon Day, a Chippeway Indian (Ojibwa Indian); Red Bird, a Chippeway Indian (Ojibwa Indian); Red Cloud, a Dakota Sioux Indian (Oglala Indian); Red Shirt, a Dakota Sioux Indian (Oglala Indian); Rushing Bear, a Pawnee Indian (Arikara Indian); Striker, an Apache Indian; True Eagle, a Missouria Indian (Missouri Indian); White Shield, a Southern Cheyenne Indian (Cheyenne Indian); Wetcúnie, an Otoes Indian (Oto Indian); and Young Whirlwind, a Southern Cheyenne Indian (Cheyenne Indian).
      - Agate Arrow Point, a Warm Springs Indian (Salish Indian), 1888 (Box 19, Folder 1389)
        Card with a printing error. The image depicts White Swan, a Lower Yanktonas Sioux (Ponca Indian)
      - Big Snake, a Winnebago Indian (Ponca Indian), 1888 (Box 19, Folder 1390)
      - Cayatanita, a Navajo Indian, 1888 (Box 19, Folder 1391)
      - Hairy Bear, a Winnebago Indian (Ponca Indian), 1888 (Box 19, Folder 1392)
      - Keokuk, a Sac & Fox Indian, 1888 (Box 19, Folder 1393)
      - Red Bird, a Chippeway Indian (Ojibwa Indian), 1888 (Box 19, Folder 1394)
      - Sitting Bull, a Dakota Sioux Indian (Hunkpapa Indian), 1888 (Box 19, Folder 1395)
      - White Swan, a Lower Yanktonas Sioux (Ponca Indian), 1888 (Box 19, Folder 1396)
        Card with a printing error. The image depicts British, an Ioway Indian (Iowa Indian).
  - Playing Cards
    - The American Indian Souvenir Playing Cards (Los Angeles, California: Lazarus & Melzer), 1900 (Box 19, Folder 1397)
      Cards with halftone illustrations that depict Pueblo Indians and their environs from photographs created by Adam Clark Vroman.
    - Haynes Souvenir Playing Cards, Yellowstone National Park (Saint Paul, Minnesota: F. Jay Haynes), 1904 (Box 19, Folder 1398)
      Cards with halftone illustrations that depict views in Yellowstone National Park created by Frank Jay Haynes.
    - Denver & Rio Grande Souvenir Playing Cards: 53 Principal Views Along the Line (Kansas City, Missouri: Van Noy Inter-State Company), circa 1917-1926 (Box 19, Folder 1399)
      Cards with halftone illustrations that depict views along the railway lines of the Denver and Rio Grande Railroad Company with images chiefly created by William Henry Jackson.
  - Press Kit for The Shadow Catcher, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 1400-1402)
    Press kit related to the documentary film biography of Edward Sheriff Curtis, The Shadow Catcher, produced by Phoenix Films, Inc. Material includes correspondence, copy photographs of images depicting Curtis and American Indians, and photocopies of newspaper reviews of the film.